Contact

jerome@jwd.nyc

www.linkedin.com/in/jerome-w-dewald-23b4851a3 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Startups
Business Strategy
Sales Management

Jerome W. Dewald

Bachelor of Science in Psychology, Minors in Computer Science, Natural Sciences (chemistry, math, physics, etc) New York, New York

Summary

Over 40 years of experience starting entrepreneurial ventures, organizing and training consultative salespeople. Extensive project management experience. International real estate investing experience. Sales experience.

Capable system designer and coder. Knowledgeable (but not proficient) on all aspects of AI and ML. Academic background in computer science, natural sciences (chemistry, math, physics, etc) and psychology. Very comfortable selling technology and SaaS products.

Experienced political activist and fundraiser.

Experience

NYC Rocks!

Investor & Political Activist, Mostly Retired January 2014 - Present (6 years 2 months)

Manhattan, New York, United States

Retired and living in Manhattan from the revenues of investments made during 25 years selling computers and office furniture in Moscow beginning in 1990.

Moved to Manhattan in 2014 and invested heavily in US cannabis startups during the first part of 2014 and 2015. By 2016, the war on the war on drugs was largely won and this sort of investing ceased but the revenues from those investments continue to mature.

Longstanding history of political activism. Ran a political campaign to get a yes on Prop 1 in New York in 2017. Prior to that, involved in the bottle deposit law initiative in Michigan in the '60 as well as fundraising in the 2000 Presidential Election. Worked for the Yang campaign in 2020

Andrew Yang for President Rhode Island In-State Petition Coordinator January 2020 - February 2020 (2 months)

Providence, Rhode Island, United States

Recruited out of retirement by the Andrew Yang for President campaign to get Yang on the primary ballot in Rhode Island.

Trained a team of 14 volunteer signature-gatherers.

Managed the process of submitting notarized petitions to 37 local BOCs.

Exceeded statutory mandatory 1,000 validated, certified signatures.

Shortly thereafter, the campaign was suspended.

JWDA Holdings International Real Estate Investor January 2011 - September 2014 (3 years 9 months) Moscow, Russia

Invested profits from the office furniture sales business in various real estate ventures in Moscow.

Jerome W. Dewald & Associates Serial Entrepreneur - Office Furniture Sales June 1990 - December 2010 (20 years 7 months) Moscow, Russia

Serviced the ex-pat business community in Moscow and the Russian far north, at first with microcomputers and then with office furniture from the US, primarily from HON Industries.

Built bidding teams and sales teams from the ground up with English-speaking Russians. Hired and trained modular furniture installers.

Handled logistics, including transport and customs clearances. Advised clients like KPMG on creative ways to avoid customs penalties on reexporting office furniture. Clients included the US Embassy, Deloitte & Touche, KPMG, Kodak, Proctor & Gamble, ConocoPhillips, Deutsche Bank, Raiffeisen Bank, and Coca Cola.

Fully outfitted a 5-story office building with HON modular furniture for Kodak at full retail. Accounted for over 5% of HON's export business in 1993.

Cybernetics, Midwestern Technical Products Serial Entrepreneur - Computer Sales February 1979 - June 1990 (11 years 5 months) East Lansing, Michigan, United States

Opened a computer consulting company (Cybernetics), then a microcomputer store (Midwestern Technical Products).

Trained salespeople on consultative selling.

Analyzed industry trends and developed winning business strategies.

Won the first large-scale microcomputer procurement contract at Michigan State University.

State of Michigan System Analyst September 1974 - February 1979 (4 years 6 months) Lansing, Michigan, United States

Part of an elite team of five computer specialists advising the Director of Social Services Department about computer systems implementation, a cyber swatteam before microcomputers and cellphones became a thing.

Trained systems analysts and programmers to use SDM-70 (System Development Methodology version 70).

Swimming Lessons with Jerry
Teenage Entrepreneur
June 1967 - September 1968 (1 year 4 months)
Muskegon, Michigan, United States

Ran a swimming school using father's swimming pool. After a successful first year, hired a second swimming instructor to accommodate the volume of business in the second year.

Education

Michigan State University

Bachelor of Science - BS, Psychology, Computer Science, Natural Sciences · (1969 - 1974)

Moscow State University
Certificate, Russian Language · (1990 - 1990)

Muskegon High School
High School Diploma, College/University Preparatory and Advanced High
School Program · (1966 - 1969)